

#### HUMAN INFORMATICS RESEARCHER · SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Nara, JAPAN

■ felix.dollack@gmail.com | # felixdollack.github.io/aboutme | • felixdollack | • felix-dollack

| # felixdollack.github.io/aboutme | • felixdollack | felixdollack

| # felixdollack.github.io/aboutme | • felixdollack | felixdollack

| # felixdollack.github.io/aboutme | • felixdollack | felixdollack

| # felixdollack.github.io/aboutme | felixdollack | felixdollack.github.io/aboutme | felixdol

# Summary.

Software engineer and human informatics researcher. Currently wrangling location and emotion data. Previously working on real-time behavior analysis for healthcare settings. Five years of experience specializing in human-computer interaction, affective computing and data analysis. Keen to design technology that can enhance human capabilities and experiences by learning from human perception and behavior.

# Work Experience \_

#### since April 2022 Postdoctoral Researcher

Kyoto, Japan Kyoto Sangyo University

- Development of a recommendation system for safe and enjoyable e-bike routes.
- Real-time advertising system based on user trajectories and location.
- Working with Flutter, React, Google Maps API, Azure Cognitive Service, Python and XGBoost.

#### Sep 2020 - April 2022 Chief Technology Officer

Tokyo, Japan Smart Care Tech Co., Ltd.

- Design and development of a real-time human behavior analysis system.
- In-house tooling for recording management and video event querying.
- Development of web and Android applications for personalized medication.
- Supervision and guidance of two junior software developers.
- · Work is performed with Linux, Python, Flask, Docker, Redis, PostgreSQL, PyTorch, Tensorflow, TensorRT and Kotlin for Android.

#### Aug 2019 - Mar 2020 Research Intern in Affective Computing

Atsugi, Japan NTT Communication Science Laboratories

- Designing and conducting experiments with human participants.
- · Collecting and analyzing data with multimodal recording systems using sensors including eye tracking, electro-encephalography (Biosemi), electrooculography and electromyography (Shimmer Sensing).
- Experiments were performed with a mix of custom C++ and Matlab, while analysis was done with Matlab and Python.

#### Dez 2015 – Mar 2017 Software engineer

Erlangen, Germany Fraunhofer Institute for Integrated Circuit (IIS)

- Implementation of the Advanced Audio Codec (AAC) for Bluetooth in Android smartphones.
- Customer support in porting AAC to different embedded platforms (ARM, Xtensa, etc.)
- Basic quality assurance through stress-testing of the in-house code base.
- · Work was done with Bash and C on linux machines. Additionally, productivity and automation tools like Jenkins and Jira were used.

#### Aug 2014 - Mar 2015 Research Assistant in Sound Localisation

Oldenburg, Germany Fraunhofer Institute for Digital Media Technology (IDMT)

- Implementation of different state-of-the-art localisation algorithms.
- Comparison of different localisation algorithms.
- Design and implementation of a GUI for algorithm comparison.
- All tasks were performed with Matlab.

# **Education**

2017 - 2020 Human Informatics (PhD)

Tsukuba, Japan School of Integrative and Global Majors. University of Tsukuba.

2013 - 2015 Hearing Technology and Audiology (MSc)

Oldenburg, Germany School of Medicine and Health Sciences. Department of Medical Physics and Acoustics. University of Oldenburg.

2009 - 2013 Hearing Technology and Audiology (BSc)

School of Construction, Geoinformation and Health Sciences. Department of Technology and Health. Jade

University of Applied Sciences Oldenburg.

## Skills

**Programming** Bash, C/C++, Dart, HTML/CSS/JS, Java, Kotlin, Matlab, Python, SQL.

Languages

Software tools Android, Azure Cognitive Services, Docker, Firebase, Flask, Flutter, Git, Google Maps API, Jenkins, Jira, Kafka,

Oculus SDK, PyTorch, React, React-Native, Redis, Robot Operating System (ROS), Tensorflow, TensorRT, UX/UI

design, Unity, XGBoost.

Soft skills Adaptability, Effective communication, Leadership, Problem-solving, Responsibility, Time management,

Teamwork

**Languages** German (native), **English** (working proficiency), **Japanese** (limited working proficiency), .

#### Grants\_\_\_\_\_

**Research Grants** 

2019 **Challenge grant,** Project: El-Astrocade. University of Tsukuba. Tsukuba, Japan. 5 000 USD

Scholarships

2017 – 2020 **Special Fellows Scholarship,** University of Tsukuba. Tsukuba, Japan. 82 000 USD

### References \_\_\_\_\_

Academic **Prof. Kenji Suzuki**, kenji@ieee.org, University of Tsukuba, Japan

Prof. Jutta Kretzberg, jutta.kretzberg@uol.de, University of Oldenburg, Germany

Industry

Mr. Nobumasa Ohmori, ohmori@mct.or.jp, Smart Care Tech and Medical Corporation Tatsuoka, Japan

Mr. Marc Gayer, marc.gayer @ iis.fraunhofer.de, Fraunhofer Institute of Integrated Circuits, Germany and Circuits are also become a support of the contract of the contra

# **Publications**

- 2019 **Dollack, F.**, Perusquía-Hernández, M., Kadone, H., Suzuki, K. "Gaze and head anticipation during locomotion with auditory instruction in the presence and absence of visual input". Frontiers in Human Neuroscience Vol. 13:293. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2019.00293
- 2022 Yamaguchi F., **Dollack F.**, Ueda M., Nakajima S. "Feature Relevance Analysis of Product Reviews to Support Online Shopping". 24th International Conference on Information Integration and Web Intelligence (ii-WAS2022), Italy, November 2022, 12 pages.
- 2022 Yamauchi K., Siriaraya P., Li D., **Dollack F.**, Kawai Y., Nakajima S. "Validation of a neighborhood spot evaluation method for walking route recommendation". 8th International Conference on Health Informatics and Medical Systems (HIMS), Las Vegas, USA, July 2022, 10 pages.
- 2021 Perusquía-Hernández, M., **Dollack, F.**, Tan, C. K., Namba, S., Ayabe-Kanamura, S., Suzuki, K. "Smile Action Unit detection from distal wearable Electromyography and Computer Vision". 16th IEEE International Conference on Automatic Face and Gesture Recognition. [FG2021]
- 2021 Gómez Jáuregui, D.A., **Dollack, F.**, Perusquía-Hernández, M. "Robot mirroring: Improving well-being by fostering empathy with an artificial agent representing the self". Functions of emotions for socially interactive agents workshop adjunct to the 9th Affective Computing and Intelligent Interaction Conference. Accepted.
- 2020 Perusquía-Hernández, M., Gómez Jáuregui, D. A., Cuberos-Balda, M., Paez-Granados, D. F., **Dollack, F.**, Salazar, J. V. "Robot Mirroring: Promoting Empathy with an Artificial Agent by Reflecting the User's Physiological Affective States". Proceedings of the 29th IEEE International Conference on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (RO-MAN), Naples, Italy, September 2020, 6 pages.
- 2019 Dollack, F., Perusquía-Hernández, M., Kadone, H., Suzuki, K. "Auditory Locomotion Guidance System For Spatial Localization". 2019 International Symposium on Micro-NanoMechatronics and Human Science (MHS), pp. 1-5.
- 2017 **Dollack, F.**, Imbery, C., Bitzer, J. "On the Analysis of Acoustic Distance Perception in a Head Mounted Display", Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Reality and Telexistence and Eurographics Symposium on Virtual Environments (ICAT-EGVE), Adelaide, Australia, November 2017, 4 pages. doi: 10.2312/egve.20171338

# Publications without peer-review

- 2021 Perusquía-Hernández, M., **Dollack, F.**, Tan, C.K., Namba, S., Ayabe-Kanamura, S., Suzuki, K. "Facial distal electromyography synergy analysis uncovers the relevance of the Duchenne marker in spontaneous smile production". Society of Affective Science conference. 2021. Oral presentation. [SAS2021a]
- 2020 Perusquía-Hernández, M., Dollack, F., Tan, C. K., Namba, S., Ayabe-Kanamura, S., Suzuki, K. "Facial movement synergies and Action Unit detection from distal wearable Electromyography and Computer Vision". arXiv:2008.08791.
- 2019 **Dollack, F.**, Perusquía-Hernández, M., Kadone, H., Suzuki, K. "Auditory Locomotion Guidance System For Spatial Localization". Proceedings of International Symposium of Micro-NanoMechatronics and Human Science (MHS), pp. 49-52, Nagoya, Japan, December 2019.
- 2016 **Dollack, F.**, Imbery, C., van de Par, S., Bitzer, J. "Influence of visual stimulation on distance perception and externalisation". Proceedings of the DAGA 2016, pp. 669-672, Aachen, Germany, March 2016.
- 2013 Hansen, M., **Dollack, F.**, Raufer, S., Grahlman, H.-L., Eberlei, G. "Speech intelligibility in realistic listening situations for different numbers, azimuths and movement of speech or noise maskers". Proceedings of the AIA-DAGA 2013, including the 40th Italian (AIA) Annual Conference on Acoustics, pp. 425-427.

Conference presentations without proceedings	Perusquía-Hernández, M., <b>Dollack, F.</b> , Tan, C.K., Namba, S., Ayabe-Kanamura, S., Suzuki, K. "Facial distal electromyography synergy analysis uncovers the relevance of the Duchenne marker in spontaneous smile production". Society of Affective Science conference. 2021. Oral presentation.
	Perusquía-Hernández, M., <b>Dollack, F.</b> , Ayabe-Kanamura, S., Suzuki, K. "Solitary and social smile production in congenital blindness". Society of Affective Science conference. 2021. Oral presentation.
Posters	2019 <b>Dollack, F.</b> , Perusquía-Hernández, M., Kadone, H., Suzuki, K. "Effect of Voluntary Gaze Movement on Gait

J. and van de Par, S.

Theses

Locomotion". International Society of Posture and Gait Research (ISPGR) World Congress.

2020 **Dollack, F.**, "Behavioural understanding of human spatial perception and navigation in auditory space".

2019 Dollack, F., Kadone, H., Perusquía-Hernández, M., Suzuki, K. "Head Anticipation during Auditory Instructed

Steering Control". International Society of Posture and Gait Research (ISPGR) World Congress.

- Ph.D. Thesis. Supervised by: Suzuki, K.

  2015 **Dollack, F.**, "Investigation on the human performance at identifying facing angle with respect to acoustic externalization and presentation of different complex visual stimuli". Master thesis. Supervised by: Bitzer,
- 2013 **Dollack, F.**, "Influence of the placing of a circular microphone array on the results of acoustic direction of arrival estimation". Bachelor thesis. Supervised by: Wallhoff, F. and Gerlach, S.